# **NIHAR SAMANTARAY**

Windhoek, Namibia - mail@nihars.com - www.nihars.com

**Systems Engineer** with 4.6 years of experience in the build and implementation of different services in the banking and financial sector. Around two years of client location work experience at Namibia (Africa).

[ Java, Linux, SQL, vim, SOAP, Finacle, API, JS, Nim]

# **Work Experience**

#### Senior Systems Engineer - EdgeVerve

Feb 2019 - Present

Worked on the development, implementation, and support of a new payment system in client location. Joined the project when it was 33% developed. Below were my responsibilities to complete 100% of the development and implementation of the project:

- + Development and enhancement of different types of XML generators using Java and Bash scripts which helped in achieving 60 TPS (transaction per second) from 2 TPS.
- + Python script to validate account numbers of different banks and branches in the country.
- + Creating different types of API (xml,lst,yml) to integrate with multiple pheripherals and systems.
- + Automated the tracing of logs which failed due to unknown reason.

#### Systems Engineer - EdgeVerve

Dec 2016 - Jan 2019

Parallelly worked on 3 different projects under 3 different teams. System administrating, report generation, development of fronted menus were my major responsibility.

- + Development and automation of cheque printer, account statement and 29 other types of reports needed by the client. Designed Frontend Menus using JS to display reports.
- + WAS server installation and integrating it with a different version of Finacle.
- + Created command line apps like 'automation of was restart', 'user creation/reset', 'free port finder', 'multiple patch deployment in single instance' and many more.

#### Systems Engineer - Infosys

Jun 2016 - Nov 2016

Trained in basics of OOPS, data manipulation, UI desgin using python and java. Created a replica of e-commerce website.

## **Professional Skills**

- > Java, shell scripting, python and many other scripting/programming languages.
- > Well aware of Linux and some unix based server and its utilities. Database SQL, procedure, functions, complex queries.
- > Version controlling using git/svn and defect tracking with Jira.
- > Functionally well versed with payments and loans in core banking terminology.
- > Scripting crontabs automation, CMD line apps, APIs XSD/WSDL validating.

## **Education and Achievements**

- > Bachelor's degree in Computer Science Engineering (2016) from BPUT with 8.14 CGPA.
- > Have online cerification on git and webservices.